Guide to the New-York Historical Society Postcard Collection [graphic] circa 1898-1965 (bulk, 1900-1950) PR 54
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. Subjects, circa 1898-1965 (bulk, 1900-1950); 3.79 Linear feet (in 7 boxes)
  - Holidays (Box 90-91)
    Birthday
    Christmas
    Easter
    Halloween
    July Fourth
    New Year
    St. Patrick's Day
    Thanksgiving
    Valentine's Day
    Washington's Birthday
    General Greetings
  - Portraits | A (Box 91)
    Adams, John
    Adams, John Quincy
    Adargo, Everett
    Alden, John and Priscilla
    Allen, Ethan
    Allen, Viola
    Amherst, Sir Jeffery
    Anthony, Susan B.
    Arnold, Benedict (Arnold's Marker, Freeman Farm)
    Arthur, Chester A.
    Audubon, John James
  - Portraits | B (Box 91)
    Barber, John Warner
    Bartlett, Joseph W., with sons Arthur and Walter
    Barton, Dr. William P. C.
    Batchelor, J.
    Beach, Mrs. H.H.A.
    Beecher, Henry Ward
    Benson, Egbert
    Berry, Martha
    Bias, Clifford
    Bolton, Reginald Pelham, with wife and sister
    Bours, John
    Bowling, Mildred
    Brewster, Ada and Flora
    Bristol, Rev. F.M.
    Brown, John
    Bryant, William Cullen
    Buchanan, James
    Buck, Dudley
    Buckland, William
    Buckminster, Rev. Joseph Stevens
    Burnside, Col. A.E.
    Burr, Aaron
  - Portraits | C (Box 91)
    Carl, William C.
    Carson, Christopher (Kit Carson)
    Chadwick, George W.
    Champagnat, Marcellin
    Champlain, Samuel De
    Chaplin, Charles
    Clark, Mrs. Ted (walked from New York to San Francisco)
    Clay, Henry
    Clinton, De Witt
    Cody, William F. (Buffalo Bill)
    Columbus, Christopher
    Comiskey, Charles A.
    Coolidge, Calvin
    Coolidge, Mrs.
    Coolidge, Victoria Moor (mother of the president)
    Cooper, James Fenimore
    Cooper, Mrs. William (Elizabeth Fenimore)
    Copley, John Singleton
    Corcoran, William Wilson
    Cormack, Rennie (singer of "Navajo Rag")
    Crane, Rev. Caroline Bartlett (pencil portrait)
    Crapo, Henry H., with Josiah W. Begole
    Custer, George Armstrong
  - Portraits | D (Box 91)
    Davis, Jessie Bartlett
    Dearborn, Henry
    De Groot, Adelaide Milton
    de Koven, Reginald
    Dempsey, Jack
    Dewey, George, Admiral
    Dewey, Thomas E., Governor of New York and family, with Governor Earl Warren of California and family
    Dietschman, Franzl
    Durant, Henry Fowle
  - Portraits | E (Box 91)
    Eames, Emma
    Earp, Wyatt
    Embury, Philip
    Emerson, Ralph Waldo
    Emmett, Daniel D.
  - Portraits | F (Box 91)
    Faversham, William
    Filmore, Millard
    Fisher, Mrs. A.V.
    Flanagan, Edward J. ("Father Flanagan")
    Foote, Arthur
    Fowler, Robert L., Jr.
    "FRANCIS"
    Fraser, Simon (marker in Stillwater, Saratoga Co., N.Y., inscribed "HERE FRAZER FELL," 1777)
    Fritchie, Barbara
    Fulton, Robert
  - Portraits | Franklin, Benjamin (Box 91)
  - Portraits | G (Box 91)
    Gallatin, Albert
    Gallatin, Francis D.
    Garfield, James A.
    Gates, Erie Layton
    George, Grace
    Genet, Edmond Charles
    Gill, Moses
    Golde, Mrs. B.
    Grant, Ulysses S.
    Griffith, Clark C.
  - Portraits | H (Box 91)
    Hamilton, Alexander
    Hancock, John
    Harding, Warren G.
    Harris, Joel Chandler ("Uncle Remus")
    Harrison, Benjamin
    Harrison, Ed.
    Harrison, William Henry
    Hart, C.B.
    Haynes, Rev. Lemuel
    Henderson, R.B., T.F., W.M., and H.L.
    Henderson, Pastor
    Hershman, Martha
    Hickok, James Butler (Wild Bill)
    Hildreth, Clarence E.
    Hooper, Polly
    Houston, Sam
    Hubbell, Carl
    Hudson, Henry
  - Portraits | J (Box 91)
    Jackson, Andrew
    Jackson, Rachel Donelson
    Jackson, Thomas J. ("Stonewall Jackson")
    Jefferson, Thomas
    John, Augustus
    Johnson, David Bancroft
    Johnson, Lyndon B.
    Johnson, Walter Perry
    Johnson, Sir William
    Jones, John Paul
    Jumel, Eliza
  - Portraits | K (Box 91)
    Keeler, Willie
    Kelly, William G.
    Kennedy, John F.
    Kennedy, John F. and family
    King, Henry Churchill
    Koch, Frederick H.
    Kosciuszko, Tadeusz Andrezej
    Kubelik, Jan
  - Portraits | L (Box 91)
    Lafayette, Marquis de
    Lawrence, James
    Lee, Davey
    Lee, Robert E.
    Lindbergh, Charles A.
    Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth
    Longworth, Alice Roosevelt
    Longworth, Nicholas
    Low, Juliette Gordon
    Lowell, James Russell
    Luther, Martin
    Lynch, Thomas Jr.
    Lyon, Mary
  - Portraits | Lincoln, Abraham (Box 91)
  - Portraits | M (Box 91)
    MacDonald, Pirie
    MacDowell, Edward
    Madison, James
    Marshall, John
    McAllister, Paul
    McClellan, George B.
    McGraw, John J.
    McKean, Thomas
    McKenzie, Fayette Avery
    McKinley, William
    McNeill, John Charles
    Monroe, James
    Morgan
    Morton, Mrs. Perez
    Muhlenberg, Henry Melchior
  - Portraits | N (Box 91)
    Nazimova, Alla
    Nesbit, Evelyn
  - Portraits | O (Box 91)
    O'Connell, William Cardinal
    O'Dell, Bill
    O'Rourke, James H.
    Outcault, Richard F.
  - Portraits | P (Box 91)
    Paine, Thomas
    Painter, Gamaliel
    Parkhurst, Emmeline
    Parker, Horatio
    Parlow, Kathleen
    Pemberton, John C.
    Penn, William
    Perry, Matthew C.
    Pershing, John J.
    Pierce, Franklin
    Pinckney, Charles C.
    Pisek, Vincent, Rev.
    Pius XII
    Poe, Edgar Allan
    Polk, James K.
    Potts, Loraine
    Powell, Maud
    Pruden [or Prudden], H.L.
    Puccini, Giacomo
  - Portraits | Q (Box 91)
    Quincy, Dorothy
  - Portraits | R (Box 91)
    Randolph, John
    Rauschenbusch, Walter
    Revere, Paul
    Riffle, Mable
    Robertson, Forbes
    Sheridan, Richard Brinsley
  - Portraits | Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Box 91)
  - Portraits | Roosevelt, Theodore (Box 91)
    See also the lenticular print card of Theodore Roosevelt filed with the Unusual Postcards in box 95.When tilted it displays alternate images of Roosevelt and the White House.
  - Portraits | S (Box 91)
    Salisbury, Samuel
    Salisbury, Stephen
    Schermerhorn, Charles A.
    Schley, Winfield Scott
    Schumann-Heink, Ernestine
    Schuyler, Philip
    Schuyler, Catherine (Van Rensselaer), Mrs. Philip
    Serra, Junipero
    Skinner, Cornelia Otis
    Sminck(?), Donald
    Smith, Art ("Bird Boy")
    Smith, John, Captain
    Smith, Joseph
    Spiering, Theodore
    Stevens, John Frank
    Stevenson, Robert Louis
    Stimson, Margaret
    Stockton, T.B.W., Colonel, with Admiral Thomas C. Hart
    Stuyvesant, Petrus
    Sunday, William M. ("Billy Sunday"; see also his tabernacle, filed under Manhattan | Churches & Synagogues (S), box 47)
    Swinton, Hon. Mrs.
  - Portraits | T (Box 91)
    Taft, William H.
    Taylor, Thomas
    Taylor, Zachary
    Tennyson, Alfred
    Thomson, Miss
    Thomas, Isaiah
    Tousey, John Euart and family
    Turkington, Jennie
    Turkington, Tom
    Twain, Mark
    Tyler, John
  - Portraits | U (Box 91)
    Underwood, Herbert W., with Captain Mildred McAfee
    Utter, George H.
  - Portraits | V (Box 91)
    Van Buren, Martin
    Van Rooy, Anton
    Vincent, John H., with Lewis Miller
    Vorhaus family
  - Portraits | W (Box 91)
    Wall, Alexander J.
    Ward, Richard
    Warren, Lulu
    Watson, Elkanah
    Webster, Daniel
    Wesley, John
    Wheeler, Dora
    Whistler, James A. McNeill
    Whitman, Walt
    Whittier, John Greenleaf
    Whitmore, Floyd, Alice, and Irving
    Whitmore, Virginia
    Wilcox, Sarah
    Willard, Frances E.
    Wilson, Woodrow
    Winslow, Edward
    Wood, Henry J.
    Wright, George
    Wydler, Gustow(?)
  - Portraits | Washington, George & Martha (Box 91)
  - Portraits | Y (Box 91)
    Yates, Mrs. Richard
    Young, Brigham
  - Portraits | Z (Box 91)
    Zaborowski (Zabriskie), Olbracht
  - Portraits | Unidentifed (Box 92)
  - Portraits | Groups (Box 92)
  - Portraits | African American (Box 92)
  - Portraits | Human curiosities (Box 92)
    Bunker, Chang and Eng
    Bushrich, Freida
    Corbin, Myrtle
    De Faiber, Ernestine
    Fischer, Mr. and Mrs. Fred
    Gibb/Gibbs, Mary and Margaret
    Hilton, Violet and Daisy
    Kissell, Edward
    Lentini, Francisco
    Lionel, Lion-Faced Boy
    McAskill, Angus, with Tom Thumb
    Millie and Christine, Carolina Twins
    O'Conner, Francis
    Paucci, Baron
    Paul and Rose, Elephant-Skinned Kids
    Susie the Elephant-Skinned Girl
    Thumb, Tom
    Unidentified
  - Portraits | Military (Box 92)
    French
    Scottish
    British
  - Portraits | Native Americans (Box 92)
  - Portraits | Religious (Box 92)
  - Portraits | Royalty (Box 92)
    Albert I, King of the Belgians
    John, King of England
    British Royal Family (George VI, Elizabeth II, etc.)
  - Sentimental (Box 92)
  - Transportation (Box 92-95)
    Aeronautics
    Automotive
    Horse-drawn Vehicles
    Mountain Railways
    Railroads
    Ships
    named, A-G
    named, H-R
    named, S-Z
    groups of ships
    unidentified ships
    Trolley Cars
  - Unusual Postcards (Box 95)
    Includes cards on leather, cards on birch bark, a card on a cross section of a tree, embroidered cards and cards on fabric (one with a portrait of Miss Edith Cavell), cat cards (with one that squeaks when squeezed), cards with feathers, cards that are drink coasters, embossed cards of New York City and State scenes, accordion-folder cards that pull open, and a lenticular print card (when tilted it displays alternate images of Theodore Roosevelt and the White House).